DIPTA DHAR

1 am a Software Engineer

+880 17714-28757 ■ +880 18864-28757 ■ dipta.dhar.bd@gmail.com ■ <u>LINKEDIN</u> ■ <u>GITHUB</u> ■ <u>SKYPE</u>

SELF ASSESSMENT

Expert in diverse programming languages, including Python and Javascript, to develop customer-focused websites and designs. Committed to high standards of web-design, user experience, usability and speed for multiple types of end-users. Successful at maintaining satisfaction through effective customer support.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Part-time

- Develop and execute unit, functional, integration testing of developed software components
- Work in a high-speed, agile environment to ship features in the shortest time possible
- Deliver quality code by applying the best development practices
- Implement software components according to the design specifications
- Strong knowledge in unit & integration testing
- Participate in estimating project efforts and delivery timelines

SPECIALIZED IN: Node JS, Next JS, React, Javascript, Typescript, MongoDB, Docker

KLoud Technologies Ltd, ♥ Dhaka, BD \ BD Dec 2019 - Present

DevOps Engineer, Full-time

- Workflow design and development
- Ongoing support of developed solutions
- Script design and development
- Designed, configured, and developed the fully automated CI/CD lifecycle
- Source control repository design and implementation
- Participate in process analysis and documentation
- Solving a problem with a software development mindset
- Knowledge of monitoring, logging and management tools
- DevOps tool research, selection, proof of concept, installation and configuration
- Establish and maintain the infrastructure to support automated unit, system and load testing
- Possesses a solid understanding of modern web application architecture, HTTP, and complex cloud network

SPECIALIZED IN: Python, Django, Docker, Shell Script, React, Javascript, Celery, RabbitMQ, Request, BeautifulSoup, LEMP

Bizitech, ♥ Dhaka, BD \ May 2019 - Nov 2019

Software Engineer, Intern

- Design and develop web application
- Frontend development with react
- Working in an Agile environment
- Used relational databases
- Designing, maintaining and building the reusable, efficient and reliable code
- Implementing the Design Patterns like MVC to improve the performance
- Assisting in maintaining and updating existing applications and modules
- Improve system integration for software development and maintenance projects using GIT

SPECIALIZED IN: Java, React, Javascript, Typescript, MySQL, HTML, CSS

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Node.js, Express

Python, Django

Next.js, React, Javascript, TS

Docker

SQL, NoSQL DB

Team Work

Problem Solving

Critical Thinking

Creativity

Time Management

PERSONAL PROJECTS

WEBbot

WEBbot is a scalable web crawler. Its backend uses Python/Django, Celery for asynchronous task queue.

Frontend uses react. This crawler takes single or multiple seed-URL & crawling these pages.

TECHNOLOGIES USED: Python/Django, Celery, React, RabbitMQ, Requests, BeautifulSoup, Javascript, HTML/CSS

GITHUB LINK: https://github.com/rebornbd/WEBbot

IPbox

IPbox is an IP management web application. It prevents duplicate IP assign. Its design on a rack server-based architecture.

TECHNOLOGIES USED: Python/Django, MySQL, Javascript, HTML/CSS

GITHUB LINK: https://github.com/rebornbd/IPbox

Portfolio

Personal portfolio website that is developed with react. Feature plan to build a backend that can update & store data efficiently & more user friendly.

TECHNOLOGIES USED: React, Javascript, Typescript, HTML/CSS **GITHUB LINK:** https://github.com/rebornbd/rebornbd.github.io

AWARDS

- The Champion, Programming Contest 2017, BSMRSTU
- PRunner-up, Programming Contest 2016, BSMRSTU
- The Champion, Chess Master 2017, BSMRSTU (Intra University Indoor Game)

EDUCATION

⇔ BSc. in Engineering, CSE, ≡ 2014 - 2018

BSMRSTU (Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujibur Rahman Science & Technology University)

CGPA: 3.14/4.00